hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
We are continuing with the test
automation obstacle list which is
provided in the obstacle course provided
by tracentes
now we have already looked at the first
obstacle which was IDs are not
everything which means you should not
always depend on the ID property for any
particular control you can also use
different uh properties to identify your
controls using Tosca
so now let's go on to the next obstacle
which is known as twins okay and this
will look pretty similar to the previous
obstacle and you would think that you
can still go ahead and use the same way
like you used in the previous obstacle
to automate this particular problem
but let's uh first scan this module and
then I will tell you what is the
challenge here and why we cannot follow
the same process again
so I'm going back to my Tosca here and
I'm going to scan
this particular application to create a
new module here
okay so I will be going into the
advanced View
and if you looked at the obstacle we
have to automate a test step that clicks
on the button labeled I am the one the
second one on the right hand side okay
so we have to click on the second one
and you can see these are exactly the
same buttons and even the label is same
okay which means the inner text will
also be the same so in the previous
example or in the previous obstacle we
use the inner text and some other
properties to identify the control which
was pretty similar to the other control
but here you will not even find the
inner text through which you can
identify this particular control
so let's look at the module to have a
better idea so these are the two links
which we are talking about
and here you can see uh the ID is ID the
inner text is this I am the one and the
tag is a right and then if I go to the
next one so here also you will see it as
ID and the inner text is also the same
and the tag is also the same okay now if
I have to select this particular link
okay the second one then you will look
here that the selected item is not
unique obviously right now even if I
select in a text or in a HTML still uh
the item is not unique okay so even if I
select multiple uh properties here it is
not making uh the control unique so you
cannot implement the same method here
you need to think of other Solutions
so there are actually two solutions for
this particular challenge okay the first
one is uh the most simple one but it is
not the recommended one and I will tell
you why so if I go to identify by
properties currently which it is here
right and if I can go to identify by
index okay and I can select the index
and that will make this control unique
because it will select uh the second
index
but what if there are more similar links
which have been introduced into the page
okay then uh this particular test case
will fail okay because it depends on the
index
and it is not the most reliable solution
okay it is one of the solutions but it
is not the most reliable solution
so instead of that uh let's deselect
this index and let's go back to our
properties
now what we are going to do is we are
going to look at this control okay
and we are trying to find any particular
control which can help us identify this
control okay like apparent control
so I'm going to increase this filtered
items to see more controls on this page
okay so I'm going to take this to the
last but one level on the filtered items
and now I can see more uh parent and
child items which are present here or
controls right
so this is my control and you can see
this control is nested inside a parent
container okay
and the same uh applies for the other
link as well or other button it is also
inside another parent container okay so
what I want to see is whether this
parent container can help me identify
this particular item or control okay so
if I select this uh here if I go here
you will see that in the ID of this
container
this one is the right okay so this is
the value of the ID for this particular
container and if I look at this
particular container
then here you can see the ID is empty
okay
but if I select this particular
container now okay
now if you select this particular
control inside this container you will
see that this item is unique okay why
because it is inside a container which
we have selected which is already unique
okay because it has got a unique ID
and that is why it is uh able to
identify this control uniquely even
though it has got no unique properties
okay so sometimes you need to look
further than that particular element you
need to look at the parent elements you
need to look at other elements which can
help you identify your current element
okay
so using this we can easily identify
this particular control so let's go
ahead and save this now
and I'm going to close this module and
we are just going to quickly create a
test case for this and run this okay
just to make sure that it is working as
expected so I'm going to rename this
modules
and then I'm going to create a test case
in our obstacles folder
so let's create a test case here and I'm
going to rename this
and then I'm going to drag this module
right down here and you can see the
container and the link here
and we need to click it here right
so again I'm going to use the X instead
of the click right
um and then you can see here Tosca
automatically sets the action mode to
select for this particular container and
then inside this it will click on this
link okay
so
I will name this click
on the second
link
okay and then I'm going to set this
workstate to completed so following all
the best practices on this particular
test case
now let's go ahead and quickly run this
to verify that it runs as expected okay
so as you can see it clicked on the
second link which was expected and then
the challenge was completed
again this was not the most difficult
obstacle as you can see in the obstacle
list it is marked as easy but you need
to know the way you can solve this
particular problem
and as I said there are two solutions
but you need to choose the best solution
which is more reliable and which is more
sustainable
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video